Finding Aid for the Katherine Philips Edson Papers LSC.0235
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Papers
  - Minimum Wage and other Labor Legislation; The Depression; Related Domestic Issues.
    - Labor Miscellaneous., 24 pieces. (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Bolshevism, Labor and Capital. -- George Wilder Cartwright. (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Leaflet of the One Big Union (I.W.W.). (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - The Depression and Recovery Programs., 32 pieces. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Notes and a radio address on the depression, by Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Information on the National Recovery Act put out by the Los Angeles Merchants and Manufacturers Association. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Radio interview between Colonel William A. Covington, of the Federal Business Association, and Marion J. Harron, Regional Custodian of State Rehabilitation Corporations. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Standard Recommendations for the Relief and Prevention of Unemployment. -- American Association for Labor Legislation. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Publications., 18 pieces.
      - Brief in the Oregon Minimum Wage Case. (Box 8)
      - Brief in the District of Columbia Minimum Wage Case, on behalf of the California Industrial Welfare Commission. -- Hiram Johnson and Jesse Steinhart. (Box 8)
      - Justice George Sutherland's delivery of the majority opinion in the District of Columbia Minimum Wage Case. (Box 8)
      - Brief in the Arizona Minimum Wage Case on behalf of the California Industrial Welfare Commission. (Box 8)
      - The Development of Minimum-Wage Laws in the United States, 1912-1927. -- U.S. Department of Labor, Bulletin of the Women's Bureau, no. 61. (Box 8)
      - The Case Against Nightwork for Women, A Summary of Facts of Knowledge Submitted on Behalf of the People. -- Louis Brandeis and Josephine Goldmark. (Box 8)
      - Brief in the Oregon Ten-Hour Law Case. -- Louis Brandeis. (Box 8)
      - The Case for the Shorter Work Day. -- Felix Frankfurter and Josephine Goldmark.., 1915 (Box 8)
      - Minimum Wage Boards.. -- Florence Kelley., 1912 (Box 8)
      - An Act Establishing an Industrial Welfare Commission and Providing for a Minimum Wage for Women and Minors., California., 1913 (Box 8)
      - The Campaign Against Sweating.. -- Walter Lippman., 1915 (Box 8)
      - The Supreme Court and the Minimum Wage.. -- Reverend John A. Ryan., 1923 (Box 8)
      - The Legal Minimum Wage in the U.S. -- A.N. Holcombe, in the American Economic Review,., March 1912 (Box 8)
      - The Judiciality of Minimum Wage Legislation. -- Thomas Reed Powell, in the Harvard Law Review,., March 1924 (Box 8)
      - Financial Freedom for Americans; An Open Letter to American Citizens from the Committee of Correspondence of the New Economics Group of New York. (Box 8)
      - The American Dole. -- John B. andrews. (Box 8)
      - Southern Labor in Revolt.. -- Kenneth Meiklejohn and Peter Nehemkis., 1930 (Box 8)
      - Can We Have National Planning Without a Revolution?. -- Louis Fischer, George Soule, and Edward A. Filene., 1932 (Box 8)
  - California Industrial Welfare Commission; Minimum Wage and Labor Laws; U.S. Constitution and Other Documents.
    - Publications., 22 pieces. (Box 9)
      - Report of the Industrial Welfare Commission of California. (Box 9)
        Missing Title
        First: 1913/14.
        Second: 1915/16.
        Third: 1917/18.
        Fourth: 1919/20 & 1921/22.
        Sixth: 1926/28.
      - Twenty-third Report of the Bureau of Labor Statistics,., 1927/28 (Box 9)
      - Report on the Regulation of Wages, Hours, and Working Conditions of Women and Minors in the... Canning Industry of California. -- Industrial Welfare Commission Bulletin No. 1. (Box 9)
      - What California Has Done to Protect the Women Workers. -- Industrial Welfare Commission,., 1923, 1925, 1927 (Box 9)
      - A Study of the Cost of Living. -- Katherine Philips Edson, of the Industrial Welfare Commission,., 1919 (Box 9)
      - A Statement to the Women's Organizations of California on the Present Status of Minimum Wage Legislation in This and Other States. -- Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 9)
      - Special Report on the Fruit and Vegetable Canneries of the State of California. -- California Bureau of Labor Statistics,., 1913 (Box 9)
      - Brief in the Helen Gainer Minimum Wage Case before the California Supreme Court. -- Felix Frankfurter and Mary W. Dewson. (Box 9)
      - Report of the Committee on Minimum Wage Enforcement of the San Francisco Chapter of the National Lawyers Guild. (Box 9)
      - Report of the Commission on Minimum Wage Boards. -- Commonwealth of Massachusetts,., 1912 (Box 9)
      - Questionnaire on Industrial Relations and the Problems of Capital and Labor. -- Margaret Dreier Robins, Republic National Committee, Advisory Committee on Policies and Platform. (Box 9)
      - Labor Laws of the State of California,., 1929 (Box 9)
      - Constitution of the State of California and of the United States of America and other documents. (Box 9)
  - Conference on the Limitation Of Armament; Foreign Affairs.
    - Publications., 25 pieces. (Box 10)
      - Conference on the Limitation of Armament; Washington,. Washington, Government Printing Office,., November 12, 1921-February 6, 1922 1922 (Box 10)
      - The League of Nations, articles from the New Republic, Reconstruction... -- Presented by Medill McCormick. (Box 10)
      - The Root Formula and the World Court. -- Beatrice Pitney. (Box 10)
      - American Guarantee of Conquered Empire in Africa and Asia? -- Medill McCormick's speech in the Senate on., August 20, 1919 (Box 10)
      - A Peace Destructive of Business at Home and Abroad. -- Medill McCormick's speech in the Senate on., February 16, 1920 (Box 10)
      - The Peace Treaty and the League Covenant. -- Warren G. Harding's speech on, as Republican Nominee for President., August 28, 1920 (Box 10)
      - For Open Diplomacy, incorporating an article by William Allen White: Will They Fool Us Twice? -- Robert L. Owen's speech in the Senate on., October 26, 1921 (Box 10)
      - China, Japan and the U.S.A. -- John Dewey, in the New Republic's Pamphlets, no. 1,., 1921 (Box 10)
      - Roads to Peace; a Handbook to the Washington Conference. -- Includes articles by Stark Young and Manley O. Hudson, in the New Republic's Pamphlets, no. 2,., 1921 (Box 10)
      - The Chinese Consortium; Its Organization and Aims Explained by the American Banking Group,., 1921 (Box 10)
      - Why There Are Two Governments in China. -- China Trade Bureau, Incorporated. Constitution of the Far Eastern Republic,., 1921 (Box 10)
      - The United States and Japan. -- International Conciliation,., 1918 (Box 10)
      - Japan; Her Vast Military Undertakings and World Expansion.. -- Louis Seibold., 1921 (Box 10)
      - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, Division of International Law, Pamphlets: (Box 10)
        - no. 40 -- The Consortium; The Official Text of the Four-Power Agreement for a Loan to China and Relevant Documents. (Box 10)
        - no. 41 -- Outer Mongolia; Treaties and Agreements. (Box 10)
        - no. 42 -- Shantung; Treaties and Agreements. (Box 10)
        - no. 45 -- The Sino-Japanese Negotiations of., 1915 (Box 10)
      - After-War Messages to the American People: Kings, German and American. -- Carrie C. Catt. (Box 10)
      - Summary of the text of the League of Nations Covenant. (Box 10)
      - Without a Friend. How the Government Stands Alone and Undefended as the Fight... for Special Financial Benefits and other Privileges Goes Unflaggingly On. -- Charles S. Thomas, in the American Bar Association Journal. (Box 10)
      - League of Nations Herald,., October 15, 1924 (Box 10)
  - Pan-Pacific Women's Conference; Conference on the Limitation of Armament.
    - Publications On Women's Activities in the Orient., 7 pieces. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Women's Conference Miscellaneous., 41 pieces. (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Calling cards, news clippings, etc., concerning the Pan-Pacific Women's Conference. (Box 11)
      - Provisional rules of the Pan-Pacific Women's Association. (Box 11)
      - Resolutions and recommendations of the second conference. (Box 11)
    - Women's Conference Publications., 24 pieces. (Box 11)
      - Official proceedings and publications of the Pan-Pacific Women's Conferences. (Box 11)
      - Publications concerning the Conferences. (Box 11)
    - Microfilm Reel Concerning The Pan-Pacific Women's Conference, Honolulu,., August 1930 (Box 11)
    - Conference on the Limitation Of Armament, Reports., 4 pieces. (Box 11)
      First Plenary Session.
      Second Plenary Session.
      Third Plenary Session.
      Fourth Plenary Session.
  - Conference on the Limitation of Armament.
    - Conference on the Limitation of Armament, Reports., 3 pieces. (Box 12)
      Fifth Plenary Session
      Sixth Plenary Session
      Seventh Plenary Session
    - Committee Reports., 30 pieces.
      - Report of the Committee on New Weapons of Warfare. (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Report of the Committee on Limitation of Naval Armament. (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Department of State, Division of Current Information, Summary of Foreign Reactions to the Conference. (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Analysis of petitions and resolutions received from the American public concerning the Conference. (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Reports on the 2nd-11th Joint Meetings of the Committee on Limitation of Armaments and the Sub-Committee on Naval Limitation. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Committee Reports., 11 pieces.
      - Report on the 17th and 25th Meetings of the Committee on Pacific and Far Eastern Questions. (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Report on the 16th and 17th Meetings of the Committee on Limitation of Armament. (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Report of the subcommittee on the Pacific and Far Eastern Questions. (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Report on the use of Aircraft Adopted by the Advisory Committee. (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Report on the Opium Question for the American Delegation Only. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Advisory Committee to the American Delegation., 21 and 67 pieces. (Box 12, Folder 3 and 4)
      List of members of the Advisory Committee to the American Delegation.
      Minutes of the Meetings of the Advisory Committee.
      Committee on General Information of the Advisory Committee, News Summary.
    - Miscellaneous., 25 pieces. (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Letters and resolutions on the Conference. (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - List of Areas Leased to China by Foreign Countries. (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Report of the German Commercial Attache at Rome to his Government. (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Memorandum of the Special Delegation of the Far Eastern Republic. (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - The Chinese People's Manifesto on the Twenty-one Demands. (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - List of Delegations and their Personnel, Conference on the Limitation of Naval Armament. (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Address of Charles Evans Hughes... on Assuming the Duties of Presiding Officer at the Conference. (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Article by Walter George Smith: Disarmament Conference in Washington... (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - -- Newspaper Clippings on the Conference. (Box 12, Othertype Envelope)
  - Charles Farwell Edson and The Edson Family.
    - Farwell Family Papers., 8 pieces. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Letters, etc., Concerning The Edson Family., 11 pieces. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Charles Farwell Edson, Business and Professional Material., 88 pieces. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Charles Farwell Edson,., 1912-1913; 34 pieces. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Edson Family Letters,., 1860-1900; 97 & 125 pieces. (Box 13, Othertype Envelopes 5 & 6)
- Photographs and Drawings
  - Framed photographs of Hiram Johnson, Mrs. Woodruff, and Charles Farwell Edson, Jr. (Box 15)
  - Framed drawing of labor and capital in England. (Box 15)
  - Memorabilia of Katherine Philips Edson.
    - Memorabilia., 63 pieces.; Calling cards, Republican National Convention admittance card, invitation from President and Mrs. Calvin Coolidge for luncheon, etc. (Box 14, Envelope 1)
    - Photographs and Newspaper Clippings., 24 pieces.; Various photographs of Katherine Philips Edson, alone and with others, and a photograph of Meyer Lissner. (Box 14, Envelope 2)
    - Photograph and Memorabilia., 2 pieces.
      - Photograph of Hiram Johnson. (Box 14, Envelope 3)
      - Souvenir of memorial to James A. Garfield. (Box 14, Envelope 3)
    - Miscellaneous., 9 pieces.
      - Medals and badges commemorating various conventions. (Box 14)
      - Picture of the First National Convention of the Progressive Party, Chicago,., August 6, 1912 (Box 14)
      - Booklet given to Katherine Philips Edson in appreciation of her work for equal suffrage, signed by friends, among them Meyer Lissner and Edward A. Dickson. (Box 14)
      - Desk name-plate given to Katherine Philips Edson by the U.S. State Department to mark her place at the table of the Advisory Committee at the Conference on the Limitation of Armament,., 1921-1922 (Box 14)
      - 57th Commencement Program of the University of California, Berkeley, on the graduation of Philips J. Edson. (Box 14)
      - Photographs and photo-engraving cuts of Katherine Philips Edson and her son. (Box 14)
      - Copy of the will of Isabella W. Blaney,, bequeathing $2500 to Katherine Philips Edson., 1932 (Box 14)
- Certificates of Appointment
  - Certificates of appointment, etc., of Katherine Philips Edson. (Box 16)
- Scrapbooks
  - Two scrapbooks of Katherine Philips Edson's activities. (Box 17)
  - Scrapbooks of Charles Farwell Edson concerning the Los Angeles Symphony Orchestra. (Box 16, 18)